# Yousef Suleiman

708-541-0259 | yousefsuleiman10@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/yousef-suleiman-4ba75a242 yojoecapital.github.io/portfolio

#### **SUMMARY**

Passionate and hardworking graduate with 2 years of internship experience in business technology. Proficient in a wide range of programming languages and frameworks, with a solid background in Computer Science and Artificial Intelligence. Currently seeking a role in full stack software development with a company that values collaboration and creativity.

#### **EDUCATION**

Illinois Institute of Technology, Chicago, IL

MAY 2024

Master of Applied Science, Artificial Intelligence, GPA 3.90 Bachelor of Science, Computer Science, GPA 3.85

#### **SKILLS**

- Programming Languages: C#, C, Java, Python, JavaScript, TypeScript, T-SQL, SQLite
- Frameworks & Libraries: .NET, .NET Core, React, SvelteKit, Entity Framework, Prisma
- Machine Learning: TensorFlow, PyTorch
- Web Technologies: HTML, CSS, JQuery, Tailwind CSS
- Development Tools: Linux, Git, Unity
  Design Tools: LaTeX, Blender, Moho

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### **Development Operations Intern**

DataServ, St. Louis, MO

JUN 2023 - present

- Collaborated with DevOps team to integrate customized data-load solutions for over 100 unique clients, leveraging backend development skills, utilizing shell scripts, and job scheduling.
- Optimized T-SQL database operations by consolidating tables with multiple triggers into a singular, more concise trigger, leading to significant performance improvements.
- Standardized and migrated data-load and import workflows for 12 different client solutions from Tidal to JAMS job scheduler.

## **Business Technology Intern**

IAA, Westchester, IL

DEC 2022 - FEB 2023

JUN 2022 - JUL 2022

- Created a REST API for efficiently populating internal client metric reports using ASP.NET MVC, C#, and T-SQL.
- Conducted QA testing for business rule engine implementation on vehicle title and registration forms, ensuring accuracy and compliance with company standards.
- Led a team of 2 other interns in scripting and delivering voice lines for a marketing animation presented during a meeting with executives and fellow interns.

#### PROJECT EXPERIENCE

### **Quran Dojo (Web Application)**

SEP 2022 - present

- Designing and developing a web application to enhance Quranic studies for students and teachers.
- Initiated project using ASP.NET and Entity Framework then later transitioned to SvelteKit and Prisma for improved user experience and financially viable hosting options.
- Intending to enrich Quranic studies by implementing the application in various Quran institutes, beginning with Mosque Foundation Education Center.

## Jen (Multiplayer Turn-Based Game)

DEC 2022 - JUN 2023

- Built a multiplayer turn-based video game focusing on strategy and player collaboration.
- Modeled game entities with Blender and programmed in C# under Unity's game engine.
- Planning to publish 'Jen' on Steam.

## PokeScanner (Image Classifier)

AUG 2022 - DEC 2022

MAR 2020

- Engaged in a team of 6 students to design a Pokemon image classifier web application in React.
- Managed training and fine tuning of a Convolutional Neural Network model with TensorFlow.
- Presented the project during Innovation Day at Illinois Tech, demonstrating application use cases as a videogame companion and TV show guide.

## **VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE**

**Quran Teacher** AUG 2018 - present

Mosque Foundation Education Center, Bridgeview, IL

- Guiding students in Quranic studies, providing personalized assistance tailored to ages ranging from 13 to 18.
- Facilitated pronunciation and comprehension of Arabic text through reading exercises and class discussions.
- Fostered a supportive learning environment by encouraging collaboration and camaraderie.

## **HONORS AND ACHIEVEMENTS**

Summa Cum Laude, Illinois Tech
 Dean's List, Illinois Tech
 2021, 2022, 2023, 2024

Early acceptance to Accelerated Master's Program, Illinois Tech

Valedictorian, Universal High School
 MAY 2020